ขอขอบคุณทุกๆท่านที่เข้ามารับชม รับฟังกัน
นี้คือสิ่งที่ยอดเยี่ยมมากสำหรับทีม Acala และฉัน
คิดว่าทุกคนต้องอยู่กับ
ทุกๆคน
ในกิจกรรมที่คุณสามารถทำได้จริง
ในการพูดคุยเรื่อง crypto กับผู้คน
ที่นอกเหนือจากบนทวิตเตอร์
หรือ เทเลแกรม นี้เป็นสิ่งที่ยอดเยี่ยมมากๆที่
ได้อยู่ร่วมกับทุกคนในวันนี้ ฉับซาบซึ้งใจที่คุณ
ได้สละเวลามา ฉันได้พบ
บางคนที่ขับรถไกลมาจาก lowa ฉันซึ่งบิน
มาจาก Sao Paulo Brazil พวกเราได้พบกับ
เพื่อนร่วมทีมซึ่งมาจาก
Atlanta และ New York และ L.A พวกเราตื่นเต้นเป็นอย่างมาก
ที่มาอยู่ที่นี้พร้อมกับพวกคุณใน Chicago
ฉันจะพยายามทำให้ส่วนของฉัน
นั้นกระชับที่สุด โดยฉันมี
สไลด์มากมาย ที่อาจจะทำให้ฉันต้องใช้เวลา
กับมันนานหน่อย
แต่ฉันจะเล่าคร่าวๆเกี่ยวกับ
พื้นฐานของ Polkadot และ Kusama
และหลังจากนั้น
เรื่องของ Acala และ Karura ซึ่งเป็นสิ่งที่พวกเรากำลังสร้างกันขึ้นมา
ในขณะนี้ และได้เปิดตัวในขณะนี้
หลังจากนั้นเราจะมีพันธมิตรด้าน Defi และ
Cumberland จะมา และตอบคำถาม
บอกเล่าเกี่ยวกับเรื่องที่พวกเขาทำเล็กน้อย
และหลังจากนั้นพวกเราจะพักเพื่อทานน้ำ
และ
ของหวานกัน ขอแนะนำตัวก่อน ฉันชื่อ Dan Reecer ฉันมา
จาก
ทีม Acala ก่อนหน้านี้ฉันอยู่ที่ Web3
Foundation และได้เปิดตัว
Kusama และ Polkadot และได้
ใช้เวลานานมากในขณะนี้
ที่ Acala ในการเปิดตัวของ Karura ที่ซึ่ง
มีเครือข่ายอยู่บน
Kusuma และ หลังจากนั้นจะเริ่มเตรียมตัวที่จะเปิดตัว
Acala บน Polkadot นี้ โดยหวังว่า
จะเกิดขึ้นในเร็วๆนี้
ฉันจะเริ่มต้นด้วย
ผลลัพธ์ที่พวกเราเพิ่งได้พบ
จาก Karura เมื่อสัปดาห์นี้ โดย Brett และฉัน
ได้ตื่นขึ้นมาตอน 04.30 น. ในตอนเช้าใน
วันอังคาร ได้ดูการเปิดตัวกับ
ทีมงานใน New Zealand
พวกเขากำลังฉลองด้วยวิสกี้และ
แชมเปญ โดยที่พวกเรากำลังฉลองด้วย
น้ำเปล่าและกาแฟ แต่
มันเป็นเรื่องที่บ้าไปแล้วเมื่อไม่กี่สัปดาห์ที่ผ่านมาที่ทำ
การ crowd loan ครั้งแรกบน Kusuma
ฉันจะอธิบายว่า
มันทำงานอย่างไร และในความอัศจรรย์
ของผลลัพธ์ และฉันคิดว่าใครบางคนใน
ห้องนี้ได้เคย
มีส่วนร่วมใน crowd loan ของ
Karura มา มีใครในห้องนี้ไม่รู้จักกับ
การทำงานของ Polkadot และ Kusama ว่าทำงานอย่างไรบ้าง เพราะว่า
ฉันแค่อยากจะรับรู้ถึง
คนในห้องนี้ ดังนั้น มีหนึ่ง สอง คน โอเค เราจะมา
สรุปอธิบายอย่างสั้นๆ
คือ
Polkadot และ Kusama เริ่มจาก Polkadot ซึ่งเป็น
โปรเจคแรกที่เริ่ม
ก่อตั้งโดย
คนที่ชื่อว่า Gavin Wood ผู้ซึ่งสร้าง
Ethereum โดยเขาได้คิดค้น
virtual machine และ เขาได้คิดค้น
ภาษาโปรแกรมความแข็งแกร่ง
และหลังจากนั้น ฉันคิดว่าประมาณ
ปี 2014 หรือ 2015 เขาได้ตัดสินใจ
เริ่ม Polkadot ที่ซึ่งเป็น
ระบบนิเวศแบบหลากหลายเชนแทน
แบบบล็อคเชนเดียว
โดยฉันจะบอกถึง
รายละเอียดของ
เครือข่ายว่าทำอะไรต่อไป Gavin ที่ฉันได้กล่าวถึงไปแล้ว
คราวนี้ Rob เด็กหนุ่มผู้ฉลาดที่ซึ่ง
เป็นผู้ร่วมก่อตั้ง Polkadot กับ Gavin และ
มี Peter Shabon
และนี้คือ Polkadot ก็จะเป็นประมาณนี้
กราฟิกนี้ฉันชอบเพราะ มัน
ช่วยอธิบาย
สิ่งที่ Polkadot ทำคือทั้งหมดนี้
ตัวเล็กๆ แต่ละตัวนี้
สี่เหลี่ยมนี่คือบล็อคเชนและสิ่งเหล่านี้
ทั้งหมดจะเชื่อมต่อกันเป็นหนึ่งเดียว
เหมือนกับจักรวาลที่เชื่อมต่อกัน และแต่ละ
บล็อกเชนเหล่านี้สามารถปรับแต่งได้สำหรับ
วัตถุประสงค์เฉพาะดังนั้นใน Acala และ
กรณีของ Karura โดยที่
เราได้ปรับแต่งบล็อคเชนของเราที่
ระดับเชนโดยเฉพาะสำหรับ DeFi ดังนั้น
แอปพลิเคชันทั้งหมดที่สร้างขึ้นบน
Acala รวมทั้งของเราเอง
ได้รับการปรับให้เหมาะสมสำหรับ DeFi และความตั้งใจเดียวกัน
ไปยังเชนอื่น ๆ เพื่อให้คุณมี
เชนข้อมูลประจำตัวที่คุณมีในการเล่นเกม
เชนอะไรก็ได้
อะไรก็ได้ที่คุณมี แต่มันคือทั้งหมด
กำลังจะถูกปรับแต่งสำหรับ
วัตถุประสงค์เหล่านั้น โดยสิ่งเหล่านี้จะถูกเชื่อมโยงไปยัง
เครือข่ายอื่นๆ เช่น Ethereum และ Bitcoin
เพื่อนำสภาพคล่องนั้นมาสู่ Polkadot
Kusamaก็ด้วย
และนี่คืออีกสองสามสิ่งหนึ่งใน
สิ่งที่สำคัญที่สุดที่คนมักจะถาม
อะไรคือความแตกต่างระหว่าง
Cosmos และ Polkadot และหนึ่งใน
ความแตกต่างที่ใหญ่ที่สุดคือความปลอดภัย
การตั้งค่าของ Polkadot ดังนั้นกับPolkadot
คุณจะ
รับสิทธิ์จริงๆผ่านการประมูล
ที่ฉันจะอธิบาย
และโดยการเปิดตัวบนเครือข่ายที่คุณได้รับ
เพื่อสืบทอดเครือข่ายนี้ของ
เครื่องมือตรวจสอบที่กำลังทำงานอยู่
บน Polkadot ดังนั้นเราไม่ต้อง
ออกไปและ
รับสมัครชุดตรวจสอบของเราเองสำหรับ
Acala เราเพียงแค่สืบทอดสิ่งที่เป็น
ที่มีอยู่บน Polkadot
ดังนั้นมันจึงช่วยประหยัดงานในส่วนของเราได้มากเช่น
ทีมพัฒนาและเราได้รับการมุ่งเน้น
ในการสร้าง
เชนของเราและแอพของเราแทนที่จะ
มุ่งเน้นไปที่การสร้างชุดตรวจสอบ
อีกคนที่สำคัญจริงๆและอยู่ภายใต้
ด้านที่ชื่นชมคือ
อัพเกรดตัวเองได้ เมื่อเวลาผ่านไป เราก็ทำได้
continue to
the the team at Parity in Web3 can
continue to upgrade
Polkadot repeatedly so the chain is
consistently
improving over time unlike more
legacy chains like Bitcoin and Ethereum
that like what you
what you got when it launched is what
you have forever
so that i think is going to lead to
quite a bit of exponential innovation
both on the Polkadot level as well as
on
the layer one parachain level where you
can consistently upgrade your
your chain.
Kusama is is confusing for people new to
the ecosystem because it's a new
concept that Gavin and the team created
it's basically a step
in between test net and a high value
main net like Polkadot I made this just
to show
an easier example so traditionally
in the ethereum ecosystem or any other
traditional
crypto ecosystem you would obviously
test on a test net
but as soon as you move to mainnet you
don't truly know what's going to happen
when you get into a real
value environment so if something goes
wrong and in DeFi for example on ethereum
it could be
pretty catastrophic to whoever's using
that or building on that
so what the team Gavin and the team
built
was a step in between a test net and
moving all the way I used like the
restaurant
dollars four dollars and three dollars
here
so whenever anything's launching to
Polkadot
they'll build it and launch it on test
net, test it out but it's not actually
in a real value environment then it'll
move to Kusama
ด้วยมูลค่าที่แท้จริงให้คุณมองเห็นได้จริง
ว่าการทำงานทุกอย่าง
มีอะไรที่จำเป็นต้องมี
การถูกปรับแต่งหรือเปลี่ยนแปลงก่อนที่จะไปถึง
Polkadot
และเรากำลังเห็นสิ่งนี้อยู่ในขณะนี้
ด้วยcrowd loans ที่เรามี
เราพบข้อบกพร่องที่เราได้ทำการทดสอบแล้ว
มากมาย
บนเทสเน็ต แต่เราเคยเห็นมาเยอะ
เกี่ยวกับ
ด้านดี และเราได้เห็นบัคบางอย่างที่
พวกเราสามารถแก้บนKusama ก่อนที่
ทำบน Polkadot ดังนั้นสิ่งที่
อนุญาต
คือเมื่อสิ่งทำลงบน Polkadot มัน
ควรจะใกล้เคียงกับความสมบูรณ์แบบ
เพราะเราเคยเห็นมาแล้วใน
สภาพ
แวดล้อมนั้นๆ และนั่นเป็น
ข้อมูลจำนวนมากที่อยู่บน Polkadot และ
Kusama
หวังว่ามันจะช่วยให้พวกคุณที่เห็นเป็น
เรื่องใหม่ๆสำหรับ
ตอนนี้ ไปพูดถึงเรื่องต่อไปกันเถอะ
Acala กำลังถูกสร้างขึ้นบน Polkadot เหมือน
สิ่งที่เราเรียกว่าฮับ DeFi ของ
Polkadot
และ Karura ก็ถูกสร้างขึ้นบน
Kusama
ที่ฉันเพิ่งอธิบายเกี่ยวกับPolkadot
และ Kusama
เป็นความคิดแบบเดียวกับที่เรา
มีเพื่อ Karura และ Acala ดังนั้น
ทุกสิ่งที่เราสร้างทั้งหมดของเรา
ทั้งผลิตภัณฑ์ และการเงินของเรา
ชนิดของพารามิเตอร์ที่เรา
กำลังทำ คือเหรียญ ที่มีเสถียรภาพของเรา
พวกเราทำ
โดยจะเปิดตัวครั้งแรกอย่างแน่นอนบนเทส
เน็ต แต่แล้วก็ไปที่ Karura
เราจะดูว่ามันทำงานอย่างไรในความเป็นจริงและ
แล้วจะย้ายไปที่
Acala ต่อไปดังนั้นทั้งสองเครือข่ายจะ
ดำเนินการควบคู่กันไปและทำให้
ทั้งสอง
ดีกว่าเหมือน Polkadot และ Kusama ทำ
these are the founders that I wish were
here but they're up halfway across
the world and
in Auckland New Zealand for Ruitao, Bette
and Bryan and then Fuyao is in
Shanghai China. Incredible team it's
honestly the best team I've ever worked
on
they're extremely smart extremely hard
working and
an absolute kind of pleasure to be
around which I know the team can agree
with
some of our backers there's
actually a few in the room so it's great
to see them and meet them in person
and of course we went through the
accelerator at the DeFi Alliance which
is based here in Chicago
as well as the Berkeley Blockchain
Accelerator
so at the Acala level this is also
something new that is hard to explain
because it's not a concept that is
from my understanding has existed before
because we're building a blockchain
a layer one blockchain equivalent to
Solana, Ethereum
what have you, but we've also built and
launched our own set of applications on
our own
chain so we can show what it's like to
build and what an example could look
like
of what can be built on our chain so
this is this is a diagram to kind of
explain that you've got the Polkadot
level that I just explained
we're launching on Polkadot to get the
security of Polkadot and the ability to
to exchange data and information with
other parachains on Polkadot
but one of the key differences and what
I mentioned about how we've optimized
this for DeFi
we do have an EVM with a little bit of
tweaks
Bryan said yesterday that we're 99%
compatible with ethereum not 100% because
we are optimizing for Substrate the kind
of the next wave of
development versus inheriting all the
the challenges that come with the EVM
so this allowed us to do things like
bring your own gas so when you come into
Acala
maybe you bring ETH from Ethereum or
wrapped Bitcoin your first transaction
can be paid in
in ETH or in Bitcoin you don't have to
go find out what ACA is and find ACA
and send it to your wallet like some of
you may have done in Ethereum
it's just boom you're in and you can pay
fees with whatever's in your account so
that should help
take some burden off the users another
thing is on chain scheduling so if you
think about financial
use cases on Acala you could
basically remove the need to trust third
parties or APIs for
scheduling transactions to happen like
in a payment system or
what have you. But our three core
products are the Acala DEX
similar to uniswap liquid DOT staking
which I'm probably most excited about
which is the ability to stake DOT and
get
a liquid version of that that you can
actually use right now there's
billions of dollars in DOT that are
staked and useless because they're kind
of just
staked and locked LDOT is going to be
kind of mind-blowing especially when you
think about the integration we're
building with Compound we're going to be
bringing DOT
and LDOT over to Compound's chain
there's going to be so much liquidity
unlocked which means so much
utility that we'll be able to to stream
through the ecosystem
aUSD is the Acala dollar so similar to
dye this is a multi-collateral stable
coin
that we felt was necessary to become
kind of the de facto stable coin of the
Polkadot ecosystem
and a few other things governance
treasury oracles these could all
take hour-long presentations
but going up a level we've built
applications on our own chain that have
already launched are beginning to launch
on Karura and will launch on Polkadot
and these leverage the DEX for swaps
these leverage
liquid staking and earning through like
liquidity providing in the DEX similar
to what you may have done with
Uniswap along
along the same lines there will be other
applications built on top of Acala as
well
where we have a integration that's kind
of rolling out over the coming months
with Current so
Current is going to be integrating with
another application that we're building
on Acala
this is a really cool project it's a
fintech company in the us
based in New York, Brett and I actually
just got to go visit them
a week or two ago, they have three
million customers on a fintech app
so what they're doing is savings
accounts simple savings accounts for
millennial young aged people and
probably around a 0.5 percent interest
rate for a savings account which is
like good in in the US for people that
are in crypto
but what they're going to be able to
do they haven't finalized what the
product can be called or
on the kind of the regulatory aspects of
it but as an example what it could be
as a customer you open the app one
day
and they offer you maybe it's called a
savings account maybe it's called
yield or something but they don't need
to know that what's really happening is
all these
dollars are being taken on the off
ramp
converted into crypto sent into this app
that's being built by the Acala team on
top of the Acala platform
which is a yield engine that integrates
with Compound it leverages DOT staking
it generates yield for these real
dollars for customers who don't even
really need to know that that is going
on in the back end
and then the dollars will flow back into
fiat
and then into the accounts of those
people on the Current app
pretty incredible I'm excited for that
to launch
We don't need to spend time on these
these are just this is just a look at
what the UI looks like for
the DEX for liquid staking
and then Karura is the exact same thing as
Acala except for it it's centered around
the Kusama ecosystem of course and then
the KSM token instead of DOT
so this is what we've been spending a
lot of time on recently
launching Karua on Kusama and right now
we're working through the
kind of the rollout plan for getting
like the KAR token even liquid
transferable
we will be spinning up the DEX the
stable coin pretty soon
and then there's some technical
dependencies for LKSM on
on XCM that we're just waiting on the
Parity team to develop but
pretty soon all the stuff will be live
and usable on Kusama
this is the Karura app and I just wanted
to bring
us back to what I showed you before with
with why Kusama
and then this helps me explain why
would we run Karua and Acala at the same
time
and why do why do we plan on continuing
to run these things in parallel
because just like Kusama and Polkadot we
will run things on testnet
we'll move it to this experimental
network or this innovation network as I
prefer
where we can test out the apps we can
test out things like financial
parameters with Gauntlet and others
and then it moves to finally moves to
Acala and Polkadot
So this is the last thing I wanted to
cover because this is kind of the more
current thing that's going on right now
and I and i've been talking about it
for months trying to explain to
people how
big of a deal this was but the amount of
KSM that we were able to
to garner from the community I think was
a huge eye-opener to
the media to other ecosystems because
five percent of the KSM supplies is
nothing to
ignore so
How many people in the room have heard
of parachain slot auctions or know how
they work?
so I think most, I guess that was the
wrong question how many don't?
Okay cool there's a few. So I'll just run
through this very very quickly
what this is i've tried to explain this
since i'm home seeing my family
to my to my parents and my family
members who don't
understand anything about crypto it's
it's kind of like
selling a house in an auction
and obviously everyone going there in a
traditional auction comes with their own
checkbook and they're gonna bid as high
as they possibly can
against everyone else with whatever that
person can afford for their bid
that's that's option one for the pair
chain slot auction
trying to win a slot on Polkadot or on
Kusama
option two is going back to that example
imagine you're going to this auction
but you can bring in our case 20,000
of your friends behind you who are all
helping you with that bid for the house
so they're all giving you, loaning you
some type of capital that you are
then able to use in that auction
against the other people in the
auction. Of course there would be some
kind of
agreement between the 20,000 people
behind you and you for
for what they might get in return for
that loan but then at the end of
say a year those people would all get
their loan back
it's exactly what happens with crowd
loans on Kusama and on Polkadot
there were there were 20,000 people
around 20,000
15 on chain and then probably five or so
thousand from exchanges
but these people were all supporters of
Karua and
they contributed KSM in return for what
ended up being
19 at least 19 KAR
our native token per each KSM
and those tokens didn't go to us we
aren't able to touch any of those those
were all locked
as our stake or as our bid for that slot
so totally new concept totally different
spin on like
what we saw with ICOs for for raising
money back in the day teams were able to
just
spin up a white paper and a website and
take the money and run
in this case like I said we don't touch
any of it and people actually get their
loan back at the end of one year in the
case of Kusama and on Polkadot it'll be
two years
so this is where we are
so this is where we are right now it's
like what is it June 24th so we're in
we're in the middle of the second
auction so Karua won the first auction
we are like I said in the process of
launching
and then there's a couple teams that are
kind of in the lead for the second
auction
this will move to the third fourth and
fifth over time this is these are the
first
five slots over time Kusama will scale
up to
a hundred or more pair chains so that
means a hundred
or more Ethereums or Solana's or Tezos
all
in one ecosystem and the same thing on
Polkadot 100 or more
so this is just to show you what
happened in the last couple weeks so we
opened up our crowd loan which is like
hey
you can support us and these
these KSM were coming to our crowd loan
they were also coming to other teams who
were
also competing in the auction and then
this is the actual auction it was seven
days there's a two-day opening period
but
during this five-day ending period
there's a randomized
point in time or a block that's chosen
at the end
so you our strategy was let's be winning
at all times so that we know we're going
to win because whatever block
is chosen whatever block is chosen you
know you're going to win
the second auction right now is actually
pretty close so it's going to be
interesting to see like
one team is winning at one point in time
another team is winning at another if it
goes back and forth
that randomized block is really going to
matter and be pretty exciting
so this crowd loan stayed open people
continued increasing by
contributing more and more KSM we ended
up at
501,000 KSM and
this is what happened so at the end of
the auction the Kusama network
randomized and spun out a point in time
which for example was this green line
and then we won the auction and there's
a winning bid
but everything that was contributed even
after that randomized point in time was
locked in our crowd loans that was the
501.
Oh there's that slide I wanted
so this is right now this is polkadot.js
there's still if any of you are like
a UI or any kind any type of developer
polkadot.js um in the polkadot.js
extension we have a lot of
there's a lot of
improvements that can be done
on the kind of UI and UX of that I think
there's a couple teams that are working
on that
but it's a great tool for developers and
it's done a great job throughout the
auction here
these are the current results so you can
see like
Moonriver has 166 Plasm has or Shiden
has 93
so these they're all going for the next
slot on Kusama
last slide
this is one thing to just keep in
mind that's pretty
under i guess pretty unknown
of course there was the chance for
people to contribute KSM to the crowd
loan but
just like you may have seen on like more
recently on Polygon and
on other networks we're doing a
liquidity mining program to help
bring more liquidity to Karura when we
launch
so for people providing liquidity to the
DEX taking out stable coin loans and
then
doing liquid KSM staking there will be a
massive amount so 19%
of the first years circulating
supply will come from liquidity mining
so
great opportunity for people to come in
and help get involved in
in the protocol itself and
if you want so there's apps.acala.network is
where you can actually go in and use
this stuff it's
live on testnet apps.karura.network is
going to be the
the domain for the Karura applications
so I encourage you to go to to this
website
in the top there's a little testnet link
testnet token link so you can
get test net tokens and try out all this
stuff
and that is it so thanks for
thanks for sitting through this and
giving me the time